<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>posts on Jer Jungle</title>
    <link>https://jerjungle.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in posts on Jer Jungle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jerjungle.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Shambhala In My Heart</title>
      <link>https://jerjungle.github.io/post/shambhala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 22:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jerjungle.github.io/post/shambhala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The bus station in Chiang Mai has departures every half hour going north. They start at 05:30 and end at 17:30. We bought tickets to Chiang Dao and it cost us 40 baht each.
The bus was a very hot tin box, though there were fans and it seemed the Thais had maintained the bus well. The ride was solid. If you are planning to take this bus, be prepared to travel like tinned sardines.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/bus.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Bus to Chiang Dao&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Chiang Dao we are immediately greeted by taxi drivers that knew exactly what a farang like me was in town for.
The price is 150 baht per truck, so don&amp;rsquo;t let them fool you into seperate trucks like they did with our group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 minutes later we arrive at the festival. Immediate impressions were good, it seemed very homey, friendly and low-key. They raised the price to 200 baht per person, per day for this year.
150 baht to rent a tent, which only ended up using for our backpacks. We slept in our hammocks for the two nights, it was very cold at night. We had heard this and thought our tough Canadian blood could handle it.
We have been in Thailand too long for that because we had a very hard time sleeping both nights. You will need a sleeping bag.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/hammocks.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hammock zone&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Pictured above you&amp;rsquo;ll see where we hung our hammocks. It&amp;rsquo;s a dedicated area for hammock sleepers. There was plenty of space the whole time we were there. Not so much for tents.
On the second day, I witnessed a newcomer attempting to hang his hammock and watched as he pulled a whole section of rotten supports down.. oops.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think this will be the same timber next year, if it is here at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of our Shambhala In My Heart experience was the hot springs! They were so lovely and situated beside a cool river. These are public hotsprings maintained by the Japanese and Thai villagers that are very near by.
Respect is very important and I would recommend limiting your nudity and noise making.
It was so nice to have a hot bath after traveling on the bus all day, and the cool river was very refreshing.
We saw a group of buffalo cross the river too and it was quite a serene natural sight. Just don&amp;rsquo;t be down river from these guys when they cross&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/hotspring.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hot Spring&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Every shop took great pride and care in making coffee. The place I liked the best by far though was HoklHong Cafe.
They had a little setup beside the yoga area. I bought a bag of their awesome coffee which they ferment with hops flowers before roasting.
The taste lacked bitterness and the fruity flavour of the coffee was apparent. The hops were incredibly subtle. This coffee did not make my heart pound like usual.
I have heard they make a cold brew version that is very hoppy. I try to get some while I am still in Chiang Mai.
We spotted him a lighter so he was kind enough to reciprocate with a cup of Thai Tea, which was very unique and the lady did enjoy.
Also enjoyed a piece of apple pie from them on our last day with our last coffee. Delightfully tart and not too sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/hoklhong.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;HoklHong Cafe&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/coffee.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Coffee and Thai Tea&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many handmade goods available there and it was a delight to have our pick of gifts to bring home for friends and family.
I much prefer genuine handmade products to the ubiquitous Thai themed trinkets. We bought a bamboo lamp, and some raw mustard flower honey from nepal.
My favourite snack was the &amp;ldquo;Fried Sandwich&amp;rdquo;. A slice of bread wrapped around a filling, breaded and deep fried. Mmmmm.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/journal.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Bullet Journal and Greek Salad&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I had a lovely time, it was very relaxing to get out of the city. There were all kinds of workshops going on and we participated in none of them.
Some great live performances too like one we saw as we were walking past and had to stay to watch seemed like this Japanese guy was controlling this girl with his voice and hands
in a very bewitched kind of long black haired droopy way. Easy to poke fun at and also very enchanting at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a relaxed festival that definately deserves your attention and you&amp;rsquo;ll have plenty of time to check it out as it goes for 10 days! In 2018 it went from February 8th till the 17th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more photos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/fried.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Fried Sandwich&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/lamp.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/beer.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/river.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/shambhala/panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Pan-o-rama&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shabu Buffet</title>
      <link>https://jerjungle.github.io/post/shabu-buffet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 04:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jerjungle.github.io/post/shabu-buffet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was the third time I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Shabu Buffet in Chiang Mai.
The first time we found this place, it was 6 PM and there was a line of asian folk waiting to get in. Still, the turnaround was ok and we got in after about 20 minutes.
This time we were early and I noticed half way through our meal that we had not spotted one farang present at this hot pot buffet for all three times we had been to Shabu.
This must be a real hot spot for the locals, and indeed, it did seem to be the hip joint with mostly Thai youth present.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://jerjungle.github.io/images/hotpot.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The food was quite basic, and that is part of the charm. There was two styles of broth on the table for cooking your food items in.
One broth was a Japanese soy sauce style broth. The other was a salty herb broth. Both were very tastfully made and gained awesome flavour as we cooked our meats and vegetables in the broth.
We decided to add some garlic and green onion to the herb broth this time and this really boosted the flavour.
There were fountain drinks available for 49 Baht, though we opted for the filtered water. There are also trays of thinly sliced cuts of fatty pork belly available for purchase but we did not indulge.
The buffet costs 199 Baht per person, and for that you get great value as the boiled vegetables digest quickly and easily. I leave feeling full, but not overstuffed.
The option to finish everything off with some green tea or coconut icecream was a welcome treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>